<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overview on Convective Heat Engine</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overview on Convective Heat Engine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Jason Delport #  Founder #  Email
Dominic Delport #  Co-Founder #  Gavin Palmer #  Information Technology #  LinkedIn
Michael Heron #  Concept Demonstration #  Carl Niezen #  Animations #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>Come get in touch on our public chat server:
Discord</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/proposal/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/proposal/background/</guid>
      <description>Background #  If the problem resides in changes to the atmosphere, a lasting solution must be directed towards this source. The primary driver of climate change is deemed to be increases in CO2 concentrations in the atmosphere. This leads to a reduction in infra-red (IR) radiation to space, resulting in a slight warming of the atmosphere. This warming leads to the atmosphere having an increased capacity to hold water vapor, which is a more potent greenhouse gas (GHG) than CO2, amplifying the problem of slowing the IR radiation of surface heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/proposal/description/appendix-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/proposal/description/appendix-1/</guid>
      <description>Appendix I – Urbanization Implications #  Global population is trending towards increasing urbanization, with some 55% of the global population living in urbanized locales as of 2018  \({[^3]}\)  , with the recent urbanization rate being around 800 million people per decade.
This trend, coupled with a summer Surface Urban Heat Island (SUHI) effect of 1.9°C and winter SUHI of 0.87°C (USA results \({[^4]}\)  ) demonstrates that the majority of humans are living in environments that are warmer than the natural surroundings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/proposal/description/appendix-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/proposal/description/appendix-2/</guid>
      <description>Appendix II - Relevant Atmospheric Processes #  Heat flux through the atmosphere as summarized in Kiehl, Trenberth (2009)  \({[^6]}\)  
Surface heat is transported vertically by the following means: reflection, thermals, evapotranspiration and net difference between surface radiation and back radiation.
The direct surface heat transfer processes relevant to this proposal are thermals and evapotranspiration. Back radiation can be affected over a longer timeframe by the improvements to the efficiency of photosynthetic processes as a result of the deployment of the technology proposed herein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/proposal/description/appendix-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/proposal/description/appendix-3/</guid>
      <description>Appendix III – Case Study Calculations #  Altitude – Sea Level
Nominal Height of Structure – 1000m
Height of HXT1 – 1000m (placed externally on structure)
Height of remaining HXT’s – 750m (placed internally in CUTs)
Hexagonal CUTs, Distance across Flats – 31.4m
Surface Air Condition – 25°C &amp;amp; 55% Relative Humidity &amp;amp; 101.325 kPa
CALCULATION 1 – Air Temperatures and moisture content at top and bottom heat exchangers #   Use dry lapse rate formula from Appendix II to calculate HXT1 temperature at 1000m Transfer this to HXB1 air temperature (assume 100% heat exchange efficiency) Use this air temperature to determine moisture content of air at bottom of CUT 1 from ASHRAE Chart #1 Subtract this moisture content from ambient air moisture content to determine condensate production rate at HXB1 Calculate air temperature just below HXT2 using formula for fully saturated lapse rate from Appendix II Use this air temperature to determine moisture content of air at HXT2 of Stage 1from ASHRAE Chart #5 Use this moisture content to subtract from moisture content at bottom of Stage 1to determine condensate production from mist/cloud formation in Stage 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/proposal/description/appendix-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/proposal/description/appendix-4/</guid>
      <description>Appendix IV - Power Generation #  The majority of central electrical power generation is done by thermal plant, where heat energy is converted to electric power. The heat energy is generally used to raise the temperature of a working fluid (typically steam), and consequently its pressure. This high-pressure working fluid is then passed through a turbine coupled to an electrical generator. The energy available to rotate the electrical generator is a function of the turbine input and output pressures of the working fluid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/proposal/description/appendix-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/proposal/description/appendix-5/</guid>
      <description>Appendix V – Global Warming / Climate Change Implication #  The intermittency of wind and solar power plants is well known. Other deleterious effects include night time warming downstream from wind farms  \({[^9]}\)   and the solar power heat island effect \({[^{10}]}\)  .
The proposed CHE, in contrast, offers potentially stable power delivery as well as continuous cooling as a result of greatly increased surface heat transport up the atmospheric column regardless of time of day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/proposal/description/description/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/proposal/description/description/</guid>
      <description>Description of the Convective Head Engine (CHE) #  Convection in Water (Incompressible Fluid) v Convection in Air (Compressible Fluid)
A vertical column of water instantiated in the atmosphere thermally separates in the opposite direction to the atmosphere. Buoyancy forces result in the warmest water rising to the top of the column and coldest sinking to the bottom, whereas the atmosphere has the warmest air at the surface and coldest air at altitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/proposal/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/proposal/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction #  The climate /energy nexus has received much attention in recent decades. The concern has hinged around a rise in measured atmospheric CO2 levels that has coincided with a rise in average atmospheric temperatures. Concomitant with these trends has been an increase in urbanization, with some 55%  \({[^1]}\)   of the global population living in urban environments. Urban environments are subject to the urban heat island effect, which means that the majority of the world’s population is directly experiencing local warming greater than global averages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concept Summary</title>
      <link>http://example.org/proposal/concept-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/proposal/concept-summary/</guid>
      <description>Concept Summary #  A new solution to the problem of Anthropogenic Climate Change (ACC) is presented. A tall structure, called a Convective Heat Engine (CHE), is conceptualized that vertically transfers surface heat by means of convection through a column of water. The temperature profile of the atmospheric column when in thermal equilibrium – that is, when no atmospheric convection is occurring– is such that the temperature of the atmosphere decreases with altitude.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
